imfdb.org 2013-12-03

# Privacy policy - Internet Movie Firearms Database - Guns in Movies, TV and Video Games

Join us on Facebook for daily polls and caption contests. 

##  Privacy Policy 

**imfdb Privacy Policy**

At imfdb.org, a website operated by imfdb, LLC (“imfdb”), we are committed to respecting people’s privacy online. We are also committed to providing you with the very best experience we can on our website. In order to do so, we may gather certain personal information about you. Please read the following policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of our website. By using imfdb.org, you consent to the collection and use of your information by imfdb as described in this Policy, and you signify your agreement to the imfdb Privacy Policy. 

**What information does imfdb collect?**

When you visit imfdb.org, we collect some basic information that does not identify individual users. This includes which pages are visited and any feedback from our visitors. We then aggregate this information with other pieces of information to improve our site and make your experience on the site as valuable and efficient as possible. 

When you register for the website, you may volunteer your email address in order to set up your account. 

For reasons such as improving member experience, we may receive information about you from third party sources and our web logs and add it to the information that we have received from you. Web logs automatically record anything a web server sees, which may include pages viewed by a user at a particular IP address. 

We maintain archives of our web logs, database, and other systems and information. Please note that it is possible some of this information may remain archived after we delete the information from its active database. We maintain archives for disaster recovery, legal and other non-marketing purposes. 

**What do we do with the information we collect?**

1\. Your personal information will never be sold to any other website owner or merchant. We hate junk mail as much as you. 

**With whom do we share your information and for what purpose?**

imfdb does not sell, rent, or trade any personally identifying information with others. 

We may share aggregate user information in a non-personally identifiable manner with advertisers and other third parties in order to present to users more targeted advertising, products and services. 

We may contract with third parties to conduct research and marketing on our behalf. Such third parties will be fully bound by an obligation of confidentiality to imfdb and may not use any personally-identifiable information provided by us other than as expressly instructed by us and in strict compliance with the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

**What information do parties other than imfdb collect?**

Some entities that have links on our site may collect personally identifying information about you when you access or utilize those links. imfdb does not control the collection or use of such information, and the practices of those advertisers and websites are not covered by this Privacy Policy. It is important to note that those entities may not follow the same privacy policies as imfdb. For instance, if you click on an advertisement on imfdb.org, you may be taken away from imfdb.org to an entirely different site. 

**What are “cookies” and “web beacons” and how do we use them?**

Our site may use “cookies” and “web beacons” to speed navigation, keep track of items, and provide you with custom-tailored services. A “web beacon” is an embedded GIF file that specifically helps us track whether you have viewed a specific piece of content. We also use “cookies” to remember information you gave us so you don’t have to re-enter it each time you visit the site. By showing us how and when visitors use the site, “cookies” and “web beacons” help us see which site areas and content are popular and which are not. We also collect IP addresses for system administration and to report aggregate information to any sponsors. Some advertisers or websites that have links on our site may also use their own “cookies.” Most browsers are initially set to accept “cookies.” If you’d prefer, you can set yours to refuse “cookies.” You will not be able to use our service if you turn off the “cookies” option. 

**Security**

Our member accounts are secured by member-created passwords. In addition, we use reasonable measures to protect member information that is stored within our database, and we restrict access to member information to those employees who need access to perform their job functions, such as our technical staff. However, please note that we cannot guarantee the security of member account information. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise the security of our member information at any time. 

**COPPA compliance**

Our site is not directed to children under the age of 13. We assume products purchased through credit card means are purchased by adults. We have designed this privacy policy in order to comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”). We will never knowingly collect any personal information about children under the age of 13. If we obtain actual knowledge that we have collected personal information about a child under the age of 13, that information will be immediately deleted from our database. Because we do not collect such information, we have no such information to use or to disclose to third parties. 

If a parent believes that his or her child has submitted personal information to us, he or she can contact us via e-mail or postal mail as listed below. We will promptly delete the information upon learning that it relates to a child under the age of 13. Please note that it is possible some of this information may remain archived in web logs and back-up archives after we delete the information from its active database. We believe that parents should supervise their children’s online activities and consider using parental control tools available from online services and software manufacturers that help provide a kid-friendly online environment. These tools can also prevent children from otherwise disclosing online their name, address and other personal information without parental permission. 

**California User Consumer Rights.**

In accordance with California Civil Code Sec. 1789.3, California resident users are entitled to know that they may file grievances and complaints with California Department of Consumer Affairs, 400 R Street, STE1080, Sacramento, CA 95814; or by phone at 916-445-1254 or 800-952-5210; or by email to dca@dca.ca.gov. For more information about protecting your privacy, you may wish to visit: [http://www.ftc.gov](http://www.ftc.gov/)

**Users Located Outside of the United States**

We make an effort to protect the personal information of all users of imfdb.org. If you are unsure whether this privacy policy is in conflict with the rules applicable where you are located, you should not submit your personal information to imfdb.org. IN ADDITION, IF YOU ARE LOCATED WITHIN THE EUROPEAN UNION, YOU SHOULD NOTE THAT YOUR INFORMATION WILL BE TRANSFERRED TO THE UNITED STATES, THE LAWS OF WHICH MAY BE DEEMED BY THE EUROPEAN UNION TO HAVE INADEQUATE DATA PROTECTION. Users of imfdb.org located in countries outside of the United States who submit personal information do thereby consent to the transfer of that information to and/or storage of the information in the United States. 

**Cooperation with law enforcement; fraud protection**

imfdb fully cooperates with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who use our services for illegal activities. We reserve the right to disclose information about members who we believe are in violation of applicable laws or regulations, or as required to respond to a subpoena, court orders or other legal process requiring such disclosure. We also reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we reasonably believe to be unlawful and to exchange information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection. 

**Changes to our Privacy Policy**

Use of information we collect is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is used or collected. From time to time, we may change our Privacy Policy and will notify you of those changes by email or post a notice on the imfdb.org website. Users are bound by any changes to the Privacy Policy when they use imfdb.org after such changes have been first posted. Please note that if you opt out of receiving legal notices from us, those legal notices will still govern your use of imfdb.org, and you are responsible for reviewing such legal notices for changes. Any questions regarding our Privacy Policy should be directed to manager@imfdb.org
